RG 074:005, Storrs Family Genealogical Collection
Connecticut State Library
Storrs Family genealogical collection
1876-1958
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut State Library (collector)
2.75 cubic feet
The Storrs Family Association held its first reunion in 1891 and annually thereafter until at least 1972. This collection consists of Frank H. Storrs genealogical papers and records from the Storrs Family Association.
RG074_005
1930-001
Historical Note
The Storrs Family Association held its first reunion in 1891 and annually thereafter until at least 1972.1
On a suggestion from Thomas Storrs of Olean, N.Y., the Association voted at its 1913 reunion to form a committee to bring Charles Storrs' The Storrs Family (1886) up to date. Committee members included F. C. Bissell of Hartford, Thomas Storrs of Olean, N. Y., and Abbie O. Storrs, the Secretary of the Association. Abbie replaced Mrs. Sarah Proctor Howe, the daughter of Charles Storrs, who declined an appointment. In 1918 the Committee reported that no work to gather information was done because of lack of funds.2
A few years later, Frank H. Storrs began his own efforts to bring the Storrs genealogy up to date. Storrs was born on June 22, 1861 to Dr. Melancthon Storrs and Jane L. Adams Storrs. At one time he worked in the wholesale grocery business in Hartford. In 1921, he began to send out printed forms (family group sheets) for family members to complete. His intent was to publish a supplement to the 1886 genealogy that would cover the years 1886 to 1922 and also to correct any errors or omissions. Storrs died on September 24, 1928 at his home in La Gloria, Cuba, where he had resided for several years. His genealogy work remained uncompleted.3
It appears that Frank H. Storrs began his project independent of the Storrs Family Association. There is no mention of his work in the Association's minutes until the 1926 Reunion, when a letter from Frank H. Storrs was read asking for genealogical information and F. C. Bissell spoke of Frank's work. At the 1929 Reunion, the first after Frank's death, the Association voted to appoint a committee of two made up of Dr. E.R. Storrs and Edmund Freeman to find out about the data collected by Frank. The following year, Dr. Ralph W. Storrs of Hartford, the Association's President, requested that the Genealogy Committee be revived. Only F.C. Bissell from the previous committee continued to serve and he was joined by Dr. E.R. Storrs and Edmund Freeman. The Committee reported in 1932 that they were still waiting for someone who could give time to work on the updated genealogy and funds to finance it. The work was never completed.4
Endnotes
1See Hartford Courant, August 20, 1914, p. 8 for a mention of the first reunion; and August 18, 1972 for the notice of the 79th reunion.
2Minute book, Box 5, Folder 8; Genealogy Committee report, 1914, Box 5, Folder 5.
3For biographical data see, Resolutions Committee, Box 5, Folder 11.
4Minute book.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of genealogical papers of Frank H. Storrs as well as records of the Storrs Family Association. Among Frank H. Storrs' papers are his notes for additions and corrections to The Storrs Family, family group sheets, 1921-1925, correspondence, 1900-1927, and notes on the Storrs and allied families. There are a number of duplicates among the notes and no effort was made to weed them out. Of note in the records of the Storrs Family Association is correspondence, 1912-1958, much of which relates to reunions, a minute book, 1911-1958, recording the meetings held at the annual reunions, and reports of the Resolution Committee, 1916-1958 that report on births and deaths that occurred during the previous year.
Arrangement
Arranged into two series as follows: Frank H. Storrs Papers and Storrs Family Association.
Related Material
The Storrs family: genealogical and other memoranda / collected and compiled by Charles Storrs
Storrs family: History and Genealogy Unit Special Genealogical File, 1886-1981
Index Terms
Organizations:
Storrs Family Association
Persons:
Storrs, Frank H
Family Names:
Storrs family
Places:
Connecticut -- Genealogy
Subjects:
Storrs, Samuel, ca. 1640-1719 -- Family
Document Types:
Correspondence; Genealogies; Minutes; News clippings; Reports
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Provenance
The Frank H. Storrs Papers were received at the State Library on June 11, 1930. They were sent by Storrs' widow, Mrs. Mary Lyman Storrs from their home in La Gloria, Cuba. In June, 1959, Marian R. Emmans, of Columbia, Conn., the Secretary and Treasurer of the Storrs Family Association, deposited records of the Association in the State Library.
Container List
- Series 1. Frank H. Storrs papers, circa 1900-1927
  - Additions and corrections to The Storrs Family, circa 1920-1927
    Arranged by "portfolio" number assigned by Frank H. Storrs.
    - 1. Mary Storrs, p. 293 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 2. The Storrs Family in America, p. 73 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 3. Samuel Storrs, the emigrant, p. 75 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 4. Samuel Storrs, Jr., p. 84 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 5. In the line of Samuel Storrs, Jr. p. 115 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 7. The Storrs Family in England, p. 9 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 8. Huckins Storrs and his descendants, p. 101 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 9. Joseph Storrs and his descendants (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 10. John Storrs and his descendants (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 11. Joseph Storrs and his descendants (see folio no. 7), continued, p. 122 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 12. In the line of Thomas Storrs (see folio no. 32), p. 295 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 13. Cornelius Storrs and his descendants, p. 297 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 14. Thomas Storrs, Jr. and his descendants, p. 329 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      The original portfolio was empty.
    - 15. Prince Storrs and his descendants, p. 363 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 16. Josiah Storrs and his descendants, p. 377 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 17. Judah Storrs and his descendants (See folio no. 33), p. 392 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 18. Lemuel Storrs and his descendants (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 19. Amariah Storrs and his descendants, p. 447 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 25. Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 26. Obituaries, editorials (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 27. Addresses, orations, anecdotes (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 28. Biographical sketches (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 29. Biographical references to families (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 31. Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 24-27)
    - 32. Thomas Storrs and his descendants, continued (see folio no. 12), p. 395 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 36. Samuel Storrs, Jr. and his descendants, continued (see folio no. 5), p. 84 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Card index (Box 6)
  - Family group sheets, 1921-1925 (Box 2)
    Arranged alphabetically by respondent.
    - Adams-French (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Gardiner-McHarg (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Newman-Stewart (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Storrs, Abbie-Storrs, James (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Storrs, Jesse-Storrs, Julia (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Storrs, Leroy-Storrs, Royal (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Storrs, Samuel-Storrs, William (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Sumner-Wheelock, incomplete (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1900-1927, undated (Box 2, Folder 12-16)
  - Notes on Storrs Family (Box 2)
    - Charles Storrs art collection (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Elijah Storrs and descendants (Box 2, Folder 18-20)
    - Melanchton Storrs, M.D. (October 2, 1823-June 9, 1900) (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
    - Sir Ronald Storrs (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Joseph Storrs and his descendants (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
    - General (Box 3, Folder 1-9)
  - Notes on other families (Box 3)
    - Adams Family (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
    - Barrows Family (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Bissell Family (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Bowen Family (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Burnham Family (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Champion Family (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Chandler Family (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Cheney Family (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Cleveland Family (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Dodge Family (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Drummond Family (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Farwell Family (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Frost Family (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Geer Family (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Gillette (Gillet) Family (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Goodwin, Nathaniel (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Gurley Family (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Hitchcock Family (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Huntington Family (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Knight Family (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Lyman Family (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Moore Family (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Paine Family; Parsons Family (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Perkins, Rev. Seth W. Family of (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Porter Family (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Reed Family (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Reynolds Family (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Richmond Family (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Scranton Family (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Seymour Family (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Shattuck Family (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Smalley Family (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Starkweather Family (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Stowers Family (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Ward Family (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Williams Family (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Woodward Family (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
  - Miscellaneous notes (Box 4)
    - Connecticut Agricultural College (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Connecticut Archives, Revolutionary War (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Mansfield town records (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Mansfield papers and duplicates (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - News clippings (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Series 2. Storrs Family Association, 1876-1958
  - Correspondence, 1912-1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 21-27)
  - Ephemera, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Financial records (Box 5)
    - Bank statements, 1941, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Genealogical fund contributions, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Treasurer's book and receipts, 1911-1953, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Genealogy Committee report, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Genealogy returns, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Map of Mansfield Center according to Zolman Storrs (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Minute book, 1911-1958 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Minutes from the Storrs Family Association business meetings held at the annual reunions. Includes names of persons attending the reunions.
  - News clippings, circa 1927-1948 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Pamphlets, 1876-1940 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Resolutions Committee, circa 1916, 1929-1958 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Reunions: 60th reunion responses, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Secretary's book, 1949-1952 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Storrs history, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)